斯塔克
Stark.
他看起来不太高兴
He doesn't seem happy.
你好，汉克
Hello Hank.
你不是应该在莫斯科吗
You're supposed to be in Moscow.
我顺路去了趟
I took a detour
你的防御实验室
through your defense lab.
告诉我这不是我想的那个东西
Tell me that isn't what I think it is.
要么就是你们照着我的研究搞了个差劲的山寨货
It depends if you think it's a poor attempt to replicate my work.
就算在这里，也需要点勇气
Even for this group, that takes nerve.
我得提醒你一下，皮娒博士，你已经被派遣到俄国了
You were instructed to go to Russia.May I remind you, Dr. Pym, that
而且你是个士兵-
you're a soldier-
我是个科学家
I'm a scientist.
那就像个科学家的样子
Then act like one.
皮娒粒子是已发现的科学技术中最具革命性的
The Pym Particle is the most revolutionary science ever developed
- 我们需要你把它用在正确的地方 - 你先是让我当你的小跟班
- Help us put it to good use.
- First you turn me into your errand boy
现在还想把我的研究也偷走吗？
and now you try to steal my research?
皮娒博士，如果你当初能在那次暴行中保护好珍妮特
If only you'd protected Janet with such ferocity, Dr. Pym.
别这样，汉克
Easy, Hank.
你再敢提我妻子一次
You mention my wife again
我就让你见见什么叫暴行
and I'll show you ferocity.
别看我，这话是你说的
Don't look at me, you said it.
我正式提出辞职
I formally tender my resignation.
我们不会正式批准的
We won't accept it. Formally.
汉克
Hank,
我们需要你
we need you.
皮娒粒子是个奇迹
The Pym Particle is a miracle. Please,
请不要因为你的事埋没了它
Don't let your past determine the future.
只要我还有一口气
As long as I am alive,
就没有人能得到那个方程式
nobody will ever get that formula.
我们不能让他离开这里
We shouldn't let him leave the building.
你已经骗他了，现在还想打他吗
You've already lied to him, now you want to go to war with him?
是
Yes.
我们的技术员连山寨他的边都还差得远呢
Our scientists haven't come close to replicating his work.
他刚才打你脸打得啪啪响
He just kicked your ass full size.
你真想尝尝那种“他来了你却看不见”的滋味吗
You really want to find out what it's like when you can't see him coming?
我认识汉克·皮娒很久了，他不是个威胁
I've known Hank Pym for a long time, he's no security risk.
除非我们把他逼到那里
Unless we make him one.
英文字幕来自Opensubtitle.org
中文翻译&时间轴微调: Zihua.W
zihuaw@hotmail.com
请勿用作商业用途
（现在）
怎么样，爽吗
You like that? You like that?
现在轮到你了
Come get you some now!
连动都不动一下么
You didn't even move.
不
Nah.
那我要是从左边来一下呢
I mean, what if I come in on the left side, right...
你看这里，就是这儿
just down here, you see this right here-
我会想你的，斯科特
I'm gonna miss you, Scott.
我也会想你的，陶陶
I'm gonna miss you too, Peachy.
伙计们，你们的告别仪式真是不可思议
Man, you guys got the weirdest goodbye rituals.
好了，散了吧
All right, break it up.
斯考特！你好吗伙计
Scotty!  What's up, man!
- 我靠 - 嘿
- Damn! - Hey!
好呀，伙计
Hey, man.
你眼睛是怎么回事
Hey what's up with your eye?
哦，还能是谁，陶陶呗，离别礼物
Oh, well, what do you think. Peachy. His going-away present.
哦，懂了，我去年那道疤现在还在呢
Oh, yeah, I still got my scar from a year ago.
- 可不是 - 是呀
- Oh yeah. - Yeah, yeah, yeah.
你知道么，我依然是唯一一个打败他的
You know what?  I'm still the only one to knock him out.
是吗，我反正是没有
Well, I definitely didn't.
谢谢你来接我，兄弟
Thanks for picking me up, brother.
噢，你觉得我会错过我狱友出来这件大事吗
Oh, now, you think I'm gonna miss my cellmate getting out?
嘿，你女朋友怎么样了
Hey, how's your girl man?
哦，她把我甩了
Oh, she left me.
哦
Oh.
是呀，我妈也死了
Yeah, my mom died too.
然后我爸被驱逐出境了
And my dad got deported.
但是这辆货车归我了
But I got the van!
- 这车不错 - 可不是
- It's nice! - Yeah, right?
谢谢你让我搬进来，我真的需要个住处
Thanks for the hook-up too. I needed a place to stay.
等你看见那个大豪斯，你肯定会喜欢的
You wait 'til you see this casa, you're gonna be really happy.
喜欢得你会根本不想站起来，等着瞧吧
You're gonna be on your feet in no time, watch.
- 希望如此 - 必须的
- I hope so. - Yeah.
然后我还会给你介绍一些人，一些非常有“手艺”的人
And I gotta introduce you to some people, some really skilled people.
不感兴趣
Not interested.
- 蛤蛤，是么 - 不，我说真的
- Yeah right! - No I'm serious man.
我洗手不干了
I'm not going back.
我还有个女儿要照顾
I got a daughter to take care of.
你知道有前科的人可是不好找工作的对吧
You know that jobs don't come easy for ex-cons right?
听着伙计，我好歹还有个电子工程学的硕士学位
Look man, I got a masters in electrical engineering, all right?
应该没问题的
I'm gonna be fine.
欢迎光临芭斯罗缤31冰淇淋
Welcome to Baskin Robbins.
要不要尝尝我们的芒果果冰
Would you like to try our Mango Fruit Blast?
呃，谢谢不用，呃，我想来个…
Uh, no thanks.  Um, I will have...
我来个汉堡吧
I'll have a burger please.
哦，我们…我们不卖那个…
Oh, we don't...we don't make that.
椒盐卷饼！热的，芥末味…沾芥末酱的那个
Pretzel.  Hot pretzel, like, mustard...in mustard dip?
这儿是冰淇淋店，芭斯罗缤，31冰淇淋
It's ice cream.  Baskin Robbins.
那我就随便来点，热的新鲜的都行
I'll just do with whatever's hot & fresh.
我说哥们儿…
Dude.
你能来后面一趟吗大厨，就现在
Can I see you in the back chief? Pronto.
这就来，戴尔
Sure thing Dale.
达比，你能…帮我招呼一下这位二缺么，谢啦
Darby, could you just, uh...take care of this idiot?  Thanks.
嘿，戴尔
Hey Dale.
进来吧
Come on in.
找个座
Pull up some chair.
圣昆汀监狱三年是吧
Three years at San Quentin, huh.
你知道了
You found out.
芭斯罗缤什么都知道
Baskin Robbins always finds out.
听着，我很抱歉，如果我不…没有人会雇我的
Look, I'm sorry, all right, but I...no one would hire me.
非法入侵，重大盗窃
Breaking and entering. Grand larceny.
听着，我…我真的很抱歉，我…那个…那已经是…
Look, I'm, I'm sorry, I, y'know, it was...
我已经不干了…我只是想…
...I, I don't do it anymore, I just try to...
我的敬意
Respect.
- 简直不能更棒了 - 真的吗
- I couldn't be happier about it. - Really?
是啊
Yeah, yeah.
哦，谢谢，谢谢…
Oh, thank you, thank you.
你一直盯着那些该死的土豪们…
You really stuck it to those billionaire S.O.B.s...
我读过越多你的所作所为我就越觉得…
...and the more I read about what you did and stuff, I'm like...
哇，我真的认识这个人吗，这就是我负责的那个人吗？
"Wow, I know this guy? I'm in charge of this guy?"
天哪
Yeesh!
你知道，我真的非常喜欢这份工作，我也…
Well, I'm very happy in this job, and I'm...
- 我也非常珍惜这个机会… - 嗯，嗯
- I really just appreciate the opportunities and... - Yeah, yeah...
所以你已经被炒了
Well, you're fired of course.
我不可能再留着你了
I can't really keep you on.
等等，什么？
Wait, what?
我被炒了？
Fired?
嗯
Yeah.
戴尔，是这样，那不是暴力犯罪，我是说，我是个好员工…
Dale, look, it wasn't a violent crime, I mean, I'm a good worker.
是的，不是暴力犯罪，是个相当赞的犯罪。
No, it wasn't a violent crime. It was a cool crime.
你知道么，虽说这件事我不会告诉任何人，也不会有任何记录，如果…
I'll tell you what, though, this'd be totally off the books, off the records, but uh...
你走的时候顺手顺走几杯你做的那个芒果果冰…
If you want to grab you one of those Mango Fruit Blasts on your way out the door,
我绝对会假装没看见的
I'll just pretend I didn't see it.
嘿，斯考特，一切都好？
Hey Scotty what's up?
我以为你应该在上班呢
I thought you were supposed to be at work?
我去上了，我被炒了
I was.  I got fired.
真糟，他们发现你有前科了？
Damn!  They find out who you are?
嗯。
Yeah.
芭斯罗缤什么都知道，兄弟
Baskin Robbins always finds out, bro.
芭斯罗缤可不糊弄
Baskin Robbins don't play.
要不要来点华夫饼？
You want some waffles?
好吧，我来一块
Yeah, I'll take a waffle.
哦，这是科特  他在佛森监狱呆了五年，是个顶级黑客
Oh.  That's Kurt.  He was in Folsom for five years, he's a wizard on that laptop.
幸会
Nice meet you.
我也是
Yeah, nice to meet you too.
那你是？
Who are you?
戴夫
Dave.
维斯塔那票干的不错
Nice work on the Vista job.
维斯塔那票？是吗 哦不，我听说过那次抢劫
Vista job?  Yes.  No, no, I have heard of this robbery.
呃，严格来说，我没抢他们，抢劫要涉及到威胁恐吓
Well, technically, I didn't rob them. Robbery involves threat.
我讨厌暴力，我只是偷了他们，我是个飞贼（字面意思为猫贼）
I hate violence, I burgled them. I'm a cat burglar.
你说你是个怂逼？（本意是小猫咪，但常用作脏话）
You mean you're a pussy?
算是吧
Yeah.
那伙人一直黑客户的钱
They were overcharging the customers, right?
黑了上百万的利润后，他就被踢出去了
And it added up to millions.  He blows the whistle and he gets fired.
然后他是怎么反击的，直接黑进了系统里
And what does he do?  He hacks into the security system,
把那上百万的利润全还给被偷的人啦
And transfers millions back to the people that they stole it from.
还把所有的银行记录全公开了
Posts all the bank records online.
最后还把那家伙的宾利开进游泳池了
And he drove dude's Bentley into a swimming pool.
你这是要干嘛
What are you doing?
- 嗯？ - 呃，我…
- Hmm? - Oh...I...
你干嘛告诉他们我的事儿
Why are you telling my life story to these guys?
你到底想怎样
What do you want?
好吧
Okay.
我表弟俩礼拜前遇到了个伙计
My cousin talked to this guy two weeks ago
聊到了一票特别棒的活儿
about this little, perfect job.
不干
No way.
别别，你听我说，这个人绝对和你的胃口
No no no wait hey!  This guy, this guy fits your M.O.
不行！
No!
我不干了，我不想再被关进去了
I'm finished man. I'm not going back to jail.
这个人可是个退休的百万富翁，曾经拥有个公司的
It's some retired millionaire living off his golden parachute,
根本就是你斯科特·朗的标准猎物啊
It's a perfect Scott Lang mark.
我才不管呢，我不干
I don't care. I'm out.
皮娒博士？
Dr. Pym?
是我，还活着呢
Yes. I'm still alive.
证件
I.D.
我觉得那个就够了
Perhaps that will suffice.
实在是很抱歉阁下，请进吧
Very sorry sir, please come in.
那不是汉克·皮娒吗
Is that Hank Pym?
早晨好，汉克
Good morning, Hank.
霍普
Hope.
叫我声爸你能死啊？
Would it kill you to call me dad?
看到你能抽空过来，克罗斯博士一定会非常高兴的
Well, Dr. Cross will be so pleased that you could find time to join us today.
应该说，非常激动
More like, thrilled.
我也没想到居然能收到你的邀请，达伦
And I'm surprised to receive any kind of invitation from you, Darren.
是什么大新闻？
What's the occasion?
你会知道的，是吧霍普
Oh, you'll see. Won't he Hope?
我们在里面等您
We're ready for you inside.
哎唷
Ouch!
都这么多年了还是没忘呢
I guess some old wounds never heal, huh?
没事，她被照顾的很好
Don't worry, she's in good hands.
你会非常喜欢的
You're in for a treat.
好久不见啊皮娒博士，退休感觉如何啊？
Long time no see, Dr. Pym. How's retirement?
那你的脸感觉如何啊？
How's your face?
您先请
After you.
在我们开始之前，我要隆重介绍一位客人
Now before we start I'd like to introduce a very special guest,
我们公司的创始人，也是我的导师
this company's founder and my mentor,
汉克·皮娒博士
Dr. Hank Pym.
在我接替皮娒博士管理公司之后
When I took over this company for Dr. Pym,
我马上开始了研究一种，可以改变原子间距的基本粒子
I immediately started researching a particle that could change the distance between atoms
从而可以增强物质密度及强度
while increasing density and strength.
我并不知道为什么这个革命性的想法
Why this revolutionary idea remained buried beneath
会被埋葬在汉克博士的研究中
the dust and cobwebs of Hank's research, I couldn't tell you.
但是，请假设一下
But just imagine.
只有昆虫大小的士兵
A soldier the size of an insect.
将会是一种终极秘密武器
The ultimate secret weapon.
也就是蚁人，呵呵
An "Ant-Man". Heh heh.
他们就是这么称呼你的
That's what they called you.
是吧，汉克
Right, Hank?
挺蠢的，我知道，政治宣传而已
Silly, I know.  Propaganda.
一个令人震惊的传说
Tales to astonish!
一个用来吓唬苏联编出来的屁话
Trumped up B.S. to scare the U.S.S.R.
汉克，你能不能当着所有客人的面
Hank, will you tell our guests
再回答一遍我问过很多次的那个问题
what you told me every single time I asked you,
蚁人存在过吗？
Was the Ant-Man real?
只是传说罢了
Just a tall tale.
好吧
Right.
那么神奇的事怎么可能是真的呢
Because how could anything so miraculous possibly be real?
不过受到蚁人故事的启发
Well I was inspired by the legend of the Ant-Man.
同时也基于我的那项成果，可以缩小无机材料的技术
And with my breakthrough, shrinking inorganic material,
我就想，是不是也可以缩小人体呢？
I thought, could it be possible to shrink a person?
这有没有可能呢？
Could that be done?
于是
Well,
这不再是个传说了
it's not a legend anymore.
尊敬的来宾们，我现在隆重向各位介绍可以终结战争的
Distinguished guests, I am proud to present the end of warfare as we know it:
黄蜂装甲
the Yellowjacket.
黄蜂装甲是为战争定制的专用武器
The Yellowjacket is an all-purpose weapon of war
能够改变装备者的体型，可以极大的发掘其战斗优势
capable of altering the size of the wearer for the ultimate combat advantage.
在目前这个到处充满监控的时代里
We live in an era in which the weapons
用来保护我们自己的武器被持续不断的削弱着
we use to protect ourselves are undermined by constant surveillance.
是时候改变这一切了
It's time to return to a simpler age,
在这里，我们可以自由公开地保护自己的利益
one where the powers of freedom can once again operate openly to protect their interests.
黄蜂装甲，一个全功能维和战斗装甲
An all-purpose peace-keeping vessel, the Yellowjacket
可以处理各种因地缘政治格局发生的冲突
can manage any conflict on the geo-political landscape,
完全隐形
completely unseen.
可同时有效的用于防范措施和战术突击
Efficient in both preventative measures and tactical assault,
可开展的行动包括监控
practical applications include surveillance,
工业破坏
industrial sabotage,
以及消除任何威胁和平的障碍
and the elimination of obstructions on the road to peace.
仅一件黄蜂装甲就为用户开展保护行动提供了无限的可能性
A single Yellowjacket offers the user unlimited influence to carry out protective actions
而在不久的将来，装备黄蜂装甲的军队将创造一个
and one day soon, an army of Yellowjackets will create a sustainable environment
可持续发展的和平世界
of well-being around the world.
黄蜂装甲
The Yellowjacket.
所以就是件制服
So it's a suit.
不要这样嘛，弗朗克
Don't be crude, Frank.
不仅仅是件制服，它也…
It's not a suit, it's a...
是件战斗装甲
it's a vessel.
怎么，完全没有动心吗？
What's the matter, you're not impressed?
哦，我动心了，但我也很担心
Oh, I'm impressed.  I'm also concerned.
想象一下如果这项技术被敌方掌握
Imagine what our enemies could do with this tech.
关于这个我们可以好好讨论一下，弗朗克，我真的很看重你的意见
We should have a longer conversation about that, Frank.  I really value your opinion.
感谢各位的光临，霍普？
Thank you for coming. Hope?
非常感谢各位，我来送各位出去，谢谢
Thank you very much everybody. I will escort you out now.  Thank you.
你看起来有点惊讶
You seem a bit shocked.
达伦
Darren,
我一直保密是有原因的
there's a reason that I buried these secrets.
你终于承认了！
So you finally admit it.
我们本来可以一起做的，汉克
We could've done this together, Hank.
但是全被你毁了
But you ruined that.
- 这就是为什么未来是我的，而你只能活在过去 - 别这样
- That's why you're the past and I'm the future. - Don't do this.
克罗斯博士
Dr. Cross.
如果你先卖给我们，我可以多付你百分之20
If you sell to me first, twenty percent over your asking price,
两周内就可以现金到付
I can have the cash here in two weeks.
就这么定了
Deal.
我们得开始行动了，汉克
We have to make our move, Hank.
他还差多少
How close is he?
他还不能缩小活体
He still can't shrink a live subject.
你就给我那件战斗服吧，我可以结束这一切
Just give me the suit, let me finish this once and for all.
不行
No.
克罗斯完全信任我
I have Cross's complete trust.
这太危险了
It's too dangerous.
可我们已经没得选了
We don't have a choice.
那可不一定
Well, that's not entirely true.
我想我找到了个合适的人
I think I found a guy.
谁？
Who?
爹地！
Daddy!
小花生！
Peanut!
哦，生日快乐！
Oh! Happy birthday!
真是对不起我迟到了，我不知道聚会开始的时间
I'm so sorry I'm late, I didn't know what time your party started.
可是我写在邀请函上了呀！
It was on the invitation!
我们没给他发邀请函
He didn't get an invitation!
但他依然是来了
But he came anyway.
我怎么可能会错过我宝贝女儿的生日聚会呢
Well, I'm not going to miss my little girl's birthday party.
- 我要去告诉妈咪你来了 - 呃，这就不用了…
- I'm gonna go tell mommy you're here. - Oh, you don't...
你干嘛来了，朗
What are you doing here, Lang?
你还欠着一堆的抚养费呢
You haven't paid a dime in child support.
你知道我要是愿意的话，我现在就可以逮捕你
You know, right now if I wanted to, I could arrest you.
我也很高兴见到你，帕克斯顿
Good to see you too, Paxton.
妈咪听说你来了高兴的都呛到了 哈哈哈
Mommy's so happy you're here, she choked on her drink.  Ha ha.
嘿，看我给你带什么来了
Hey, look what I have for you.
我可以现在就打开吗？
Can I open it now?
当然了小宝贝，今天是你的生日呀
Of course sweetheart, it's your birthday.
你是我最好的朋友！
You're my bestest friend!
这是什么鬼东西？
What is that thing?
他好丑哦！
He's so ugly!
我好喜欢他哦！
I love him!
我能拿去给我朋友们看吗？
Can I go show my friends?
当然啦宝贝儿，去吧
Yeah, of course sweetheart, go ahead.
你是我最好的朋友！
You're my bestest friend!
好吧，我会付抚养费的
Look, the child support is coming.
你知道的，有前科是不那么好找工作的
All right, it's just hard finding a job when you have a record.
我知道你会搞定的，但是现在我想请你离开
I'm sure you'll figure it out, but for now, I want you out of my house.
- 等等，这是我女儿的生日聚会耶 - 这里是我家
- No, wait, it's my daughter's birthday! - It's my house!
- 然后呢，她是我女儿啊 - 别这样
- So what, it's my kid! - Relax!
你不能就这么直接过来
You can't just show up here.
你知道的，对吧
You know that, c'mon.
是生日聚会耶
It's a birthday party.
是啊我知道，但你不能就这么过来
Yeah, I know, but you can't just show up.
- 是我女儿耶 - 你根本不知道应该怎么当爸爸
- She's my daughter. - You don't know the first thing about being a father.
玛姬，看在你是我初恋也是我朋友的份上，我得说
Maggie, I tell you this as a friend, and as the first love of my life,
你未婚夫就是个傻帽儿
your fiance is an ass-hat.
他才不是傻帽儿
He's not an ass-hat.
- 嘿，你怎么说话这么难听啊 - 你跟我出来一下
- Hey, watch your language, okay! - Just give me one minute
- 怎么难听了，我说的是帽儿 - 都别说了！
- Oh, what language. I said hat. - Stop that！
玛姬，真的吗，就这货？
Really, Maggie? That guy?
你跟谁结婚都好啊，怎么偏偏找了个条子啊！
Come on, you could marry anyone you want, you have to get engaged to a cop?
至少他不是个骗子吧
At least he's not a crook.
我已经在努力了好吗，我已经不那样了…
I'm trying, okay?  I've changed, uh...
我正常生活了，也找过工作
I'm straight, I had a job, and...
我仔细想过了，我想要好好关心她，我真的很爱她
I want to provide.  I've had a lot of time to think about it, and I love her.
真的！我已经错过了那么多，我不想再错过了
So much.  I've missed so much time and I want to be a part of her life.
我要怎么做才行？
What do I do?
先找个自己住的地方
Get an apartment.
找份正经工作，按时付抚养费
Get a job, pay child support.
你只要做了，我保证就和你谈探视权的事
And then we will talk about visitation, I promise.
你是她心目中的英雄，斯科特
You're her hero, Scott.
我希望你不要辜负她的期望
Just, be the person that she already thinks you are.
我很抱歉黄蜂装甲让你有这么多的顾虑，弗兰克
I'm sorry you have such deep concerns about the Yellowjacket, Frank.
哦，是呀，很不幸的是
Yeah, well uh, unfortunately
我们并不能为所欲为
we can't just do whatever we want.
可这主意很不错是吧？
Would be nice though, right?
但我们有法则的
But there are laws.
什么规则？法律？
What laws? Of man?
自然法则要超越人类的法律
The laws of nature transcend the laws of man.
可我已经超越了自然的法则
And I've transcended the laws of nature.
达伦，我觉得你还是不明白…
Darren, I don't think you understand-
看来还有很多问题要解决
We still haven't worked out all the bugs.
再见，弗兰克
Goodbye Frank.
你知道么，最近我一直在思考关于感恩的问题
You know I've been thinking a lot about gratitude lately
就在今天早晨，我突然有了个很有趣的想法
and today during my morning meditation, an interesting thought occurred to me and
我觉得应该和你分享
I think it might apply to you too.
是什么呢？
How's that?
原谅也是一种感恩
Gratitude can be forgiveness.
这些年对汉克·皮娒的愤怒一直包围着我
I spent years carrying around my anger for Hank Pym.
我奉献了我的才华
I devoted my genius to him.
把我的时间全给了他
I could've worked anywhere.
选他作为我的导师真是个失误
I chose my mentor poorly.
可你甚至没有选择的权利
You didn't even have a choice.
他从来就没有信任过你
He never believed in you.
很多事情我们不得不做，可这不都是被他逼的么？
It's a shame what we had to do, but he forced us to do it, didn't he?
不过，我们不应该为此愤怒，我们应该心怀感激
But we shouldn't be angry, we should be grateful.
作为一个失败的导师，
Because his failures as a mentor,
一位不合格的父亲
as a father,
他的错误促成了我们的成就
forced us to spread our wings.
你成功了，达伦
You're a success, Darren.
所有的一切都是你应得的
You deserve everything coming your way.
（提现 日常开销 子女付养费）
（还要377天才能见到凯茜）
哎唷！
Ooh!
别作弊了
Stop cheating.
嘿，怎样了帅哥
Hey what's up hotshot?
可能他没听见
Maybe he didn't hear you.
聚会怎么样？
How was the party?
跟我说说那票活儿
Tell me about that tip.
啥？
Wha?
我想知道你说的那票活儿是什么
I wanna know about that tip.
- 哦亲，太棒了！ - 牛逼了
- Oh baby, it's on! - Hot dog!
我已经按耐不住了！
It's so on right now!
冷静点行么，我想知道这消息是怎么来的
Calm down, all right, I just need to know where it came from,
得是个确凿的消息
it's gotta be airtight.
好吧
Okay.
我和我表哥埃内斯托参加了一个品酒会
I was at a wine tasting with my cousin Ernesto
主要全是红酒，然后你也知道的，我不喜欢红酒，不过
it was mainly reds, and you know I don't love reds man, y'know, but
有一种桃红（陶红）酒，特别不错，总之还是值了
there was a rosé that saved the day, it was delightful.
然后，我们聊起了那个曾经一起找乐子的姑娘，艾米莉
And, he tells me about this girl Emily that we used to kick it with,
你知道么，那是我头一次摸到了咪咪
it was actually the first pair of boobs that I ever touched.
你跑题了，跑题了！这和正事儿一点关系都没有…
It's the wrong details.  It's wro- Has nothing to do with the story.
好好说
Go.
然后，他跟我说
So, uh.  He tells me that:
她不是给人做女管家么
She's working as a housekeeper now, right?
她男朋友叫卡洛斯，是个海湾那边的帮派老大
And she's dating this dude Carlos who's a shot caller from across the bay and
所以她就跟他讲起了主人家的事儿，是吧
she tells him about the dude that she's cleaning for. Right?
他是那种超大牌的退休总裁，可有钱了
That he's, like, this big-shot CEO that is all retired now but he's loaded.
然后你知道卡洛斯和埃内斯托是一个垒球队的
And so, Carlos and Ernesto are on the same softball team
没事儿就闲聊天啥的
and they get to talking, right.
然后最牛的地方来了
And here comes the good part.
卡洛斯说
Carlos says:
哟哥们，内家伙家里地下室有个超大号的保险库
Yo, man. This guy's got a big-ass safe just sitting in the basement.
巨牛掰
Just chillin'.
埃内斯托知道我最会偷东西，所以回来就告诉我了
Of course Ernesto comes to me 'cause he knows I've got mad thieving skills.
我当然得问他了
Of course I ask him:
那艾米莉没跟卡洛斯说让你告诉我那个保险库什么样儿么？
Did Emily tell Carlos to tell you to get to me what kind of safe it was?
然后他说
And he says
没有啊，她就跟我说，是个特别高端的保险库
Naw, dog. All she said is that it's, like, super legit, and
里面肯定有不少好东西！
whatever's in it has gotta be good!
啥？
What?
老头有个保鲜库
Old man have safe.
他一礼拜都不在
And is gone for a week.
好吧，有个老头儿，他有个保险库，老头儿出门一礼拜
All right.  There's an old man, he's got a safe, and he's gone for a week.
那开始行动吧
Let's just work with that.
我就说嘛
Y'know what I' sayin'.
电话钱切断了，手机信号也屏蔽了
Landlines cut, cell signals jammed.
现在谁也别想报警了
No one will be making for distress call tonight.
报告下情况
All check.
- 正常 - 正常
- Check. - Check.
嘿，你知道如果有状况，有我在这边照顾你呢
Hey if the job goes bad, you know I got your back, right?
不能够，不可能有状况
Don't worry, it's not gonna happen.
我就喜欢他那牛逼劲儿
I love it when he gets cocky.
卧操！
Damn!
警报器已经关了
Alarm is dead.
厉害！
Nice!
好，我现在要进屋子里去了
All right, I'm moving through the house.
这门上有个指纹识别锁
There's a fingerprint lock on the door.
有个啥？
He's got a what?
埃内斯托没跟我说有这个啊
Ernesto didn't tell me nothing about that.
不是吧，这就没戏了吗？
Aw, man, are we screwed?
那也不一定
Not necessarily.
我进来了
I'm in.
一个警报都没触发，他简直神了
No alarms have been triggered. He's in like the Flynn.
不是吧…
Oh, man.
怎么啦？
What is it?
他们说对了，还真是个高端的保鲜库
Well they weren't kidding. This safe is serious.
有多高端啊，斯科特
How serious we talkin', Scotty?
卡本代尔的
It's a Carbondale.
1910年产的
It's from 1910.
用的是和泰坦尼克号一样的那种钢材
Made from the same steel as the Titanic.
喔！
Wow.
你能给弄开吗？
Can you crack it?
嗯，倒是有个办法
Well, here's the thing.
这种钢材不耐低温
It doesn't do so well in the cold.
还记得撞船的那个冰山吗
Remember what that iceberg did?
哦，我知道，把小李子（莱奥纳多·迪卡布里奥）弄死了。
Yeah, man, it killed DiCaprio.
所有人都死了
Killed everybody.
那老太太就没死！
Did not kill the old lady.
最后还把那项链扔海里了呢！
She still throw the jewel into the oceans.
你干什么呢？
What're you doing?
我往锁定装置里面灌了水，然后用液氮冷冻
I poured water in the locking mechanism and froze it with nitrogen.
水结冰会膨胀，但是金属不会
Ice expands, metal doesn't.
那现在呢？
What are you doing now?
等一下
Waiting.
还得等一下
行了
Nice.
里面是什么？现金？珠宝？
What is it, cash? Jewels?
这儿什么都没有啊！
There's nothing here.
你说什么？
What'd you say?
就有一件制服
It's a suit.
啥？
What?
一件旧的摩托车赛车服
It's an old motorcycle suit.
没有现金？也没有珠宝？啥都没有？
There's no cash, no jewelry, nothing?
没有。
No.
真倒霉
It's a bust.
我很抱歉，斯科特
I'm really sorry, Scotty.
让你失望了
I know you needed a score.
我以为我们要用老鼠的
I thought we were using mice?
有什么区别吗
What's the difference?
实验34-C现在开始
Commence experiment 34-C,
有机体的原子缩小
organic atomic reduction.
达伦，我们应该再考虑一…
Darren, maybe we should think-
缩小有机组织是这项技术里最核心部分
Shrinking organic tissue is the centerpiece of this technology.
只做了一半的技术我要怎么卖给人啊？
I can't go to the buyers with half a breakthrough.
34-C的实验结果
Experiment 34-C results...
是失败
negative.
清理操作台，准备实验品35-C
Sanitize the workstation, bring in subject 35-C.
把这个锁起来是为什么呢？
Why would you lock this up?
真是诡异
So weird.
斯考特，你还好吗
Scott, what's up man?
我琢磨…这是什么呢？
I wonder...what is this?
从下面看整个世界都不一样了，是不是斯考特？
The world sure seems different from down here, doesn't it, Scott?
什么？谁？是谁在说话？
What? Who...who said that?
阿毛！阿毛！我在下面！
Luis! Luis, down here!
真是以身试火，斯考特
It's a trial by fire, Scott.
或者更确切的说
Or in this case,
是水
water.
看来你比你想的要结实呢
Guess you're tougher than you thought.
哦，我可不想看你这个…
Oh, I don't want to see this.
阿毛！
Luis!
你个混…
Son of a-!
什么鬼？
What the hell?
就试驾来说你还不错嘛
Not bad for a test drive.
衣服你留着吧
Keep the suit
- 我会和你联系的 - 不，不，不要
- I'll be in touch. - No, no. No.
不要，谢谢您了
No thank you.
呆在地上不要动！
Get down on the ground!
你被捕了！
You are under arrest!
不，我没有偷东西！
No, I didn't steal anything!
我只是把偷的东西还回来。
I was returning something I stole.
你知道么，我们差点就相信你说的你“已经改了”
You know, you almost had us convinced that you were going to change your ways.
她们都真心为你加油呢
They were really rooting for you.
这会伤透她们的心的
It's gonna break their hearts.
有人找你
You got a visitor.
谁？
Who?
你的律师
Your lawyer.
律师？
My lawyer?
我说了我会和你联系的，斯考特
I told you I'd be in touch, Scott.
我现在觉得你没准更喜欢呆监狱里
I'm starting to think that you prefer the inside of a jail cell.
天哪
Oh man.
坐吧
Sit down.
先生，我真的非常抱歉偷了你的衣服
Sir, I'm sorry I stole the suit.
我甚至都不想知道你为什么会有这件衣服
I don't even want to know why you have it.
玛姬真是一点也没看错你
Maggie was right about you.
你怎么会知道…
How do you know about-
难怪她不让你接近凯茜
The way she's trying to keep you away from Cassie.
事情才刚刚有点难，你就走回犯罪的老路了
The moment things get hard, you turn right back to crime.
但在我来看，你是有选择的
The way I see it, you have a choice.
你可以选择在监狱里度过你的下半辈子
You can either spend the rest of your life in prison
或者选择先回到你的房间然后等我的指示
or go back to your cell and await further instructions.
我不太明白…
I don't understand.
我也没指望你明白
You know I don't expect you to.
但你现在的确没那么多选项了
But you don't have many options right now.
坦白的说，我也没有了
Quite frankly, neither do I.
不然一开始我也不会叫你偷走那件衣服
Why do you think I let you steal that suit in the first place?
啥？
What?
还有，机会可不是总会出现的。
Second chances don't come around all that much.
所以下次你在遇到的时候
So next time you think you might see one
我劝你千万抓紧它别松手
I suggest you take a real close look at it.
你是我最好的朋友！
You are my bestest friend!
你真的不想要个别的玩具吗？
Are you sure you don't want a different toy?
不想，我就喜欢这个
No, I love this one.
那好吧
Okay.
早点睡吧，我爱你
Well, get some sleep, I love you.
- 妈咪 - 嗯？
- Mommy. - Hm?
爸爸是坏人吗？
Is daddy a bad man?
我听大人们说他是坏人
I heard some grown ups say he's bad.
不是
No.
爸爸只是有时候有些困惑，你明白吗？
Daddy just gets confused sometimes, you know?
这就对了，看来你还是会听话的
Smart choice. You actually listened for once.
门的下面
Under the door.
行了，现在呢？
Okay. Where to now?
抓紧
Hang tight.
什么？你说什么？
What? What?!
见鬼了，他跑哪去了？
Where the hell did he go?
我也不知道，他就这么没了。
I have no idea, he just vanished.
立刻封锁附近街区，马上做！
Set up a five block perimeter, now!
回去！别过来！回去！
Get back, get back, get back!
斯科特，他们是我的帮手
Scott. These are my associates.
啊？你在蚂蚁身上装了摄像头？
Huh? You got a camera on an ant?
是啊，当然了，为什么不装呢
Yeah, sure, why not?
那么车在哪？
Where's the car?
没有车，但是有翅膀哦
No car, we've got wings.
来了
Incoming!
踩中间上去然后骑在它的胸部上面
Put your foot on the central node and mount the thorax.
你这是开玩…这东西真的安全…
Are you ki- How safe's Th-
赶紧给我上去，斯科特
Get on the damn ant, Scott.
为什么我在警车里面
Why am I on a police car?
我不应该在警车里面吧！
Shouldn't I not be on a police car?
这样你才能搭车通过他们的封锁呀
So they can give you a lift past their five block perimeter.
哇哦，好吧
Whoa. All right.
现在呢，下一步怎样？
Now, what's the next move?
抓紧骑好
Hang on tight.
哦，这好办，我一直抓着呢
Oh, this is easy. I'm getting the hang of this.
往上拽就向上飞了，就跟骑马一样
Yank up to go up. It's like a horse.
你抓的247都要失去平衡了
You're throwing 247 off balance.
- 啥，他叫247？ - 他没有名字
- Wait, his name is 247? - He doesn't have a name,
他只有代号，你知道一共有多少只蚂蚁呢吗，斯科特？
he has a number Scott, do you have any idea how many ants there are?
哇哦！
Whoa!
嗯等一下，也可能是248
Maybe it's, maybe it's 248?
不，不不不！晕了，晕了！
No no no no no vertigo, vertigo!
不，我确定就是247
No, I think it's 247.
- 等一下 - 抓紧骑好
- Wait. - Hang on tight.
我觉得我已经会控制他了
I think I'm getting the hang of this.
我在控制247，他根本没听你的
I'm controlling 247. He is not listening to you.
你说什么？
What?
我能提个小小的要求吗
Can I make one little request?
不能
No.
停，247，暂停！暂停！
Stop, 247, time out, time out.
快停下！
Time out.
慢点，等下行么
All right, hold on.
别，等下，慢点，嗷！
Just, wait, whoa, uh!
我要是吐头盔里了会怎么样
What happens if I throw up in this helmet?
那是我的头盔，不许吐！
It's my helmet Scott. Do not throw up.
放他下来，好吗
Just set 'er down, all right?
我有点晕
I'm getting light headed.
坚持一下，斯科特
Hang on, Scott.
是，我眼前有点发黑
Yeah, I'm getting a little light...
我觉得，我需要谁…
-t's, I need, somebody...
能…过五分钟…叫醒我…
...to hit me, in five minutes-
你好
Hello.
你是谁啊？
Who are you?
你一直就站在这里看我睡觉吗？
Have you been standing there watching me sleep this whole time?
是的
Yes.
为什么啊
Why?
因为上次你在这里的时候你偷了点东西
Because the last time you were here you stole something.
哦…
Oh. Oh!
嘿，听我说
Hey, look.
（世界上体形最大的蚂蚁之一，因螫人时产生剧烈疼痛而得名）
哇哦！
Whoa!
Paraponera clavata（子弹蚁拉丁学名）
Paraponera clavata.
来自热带地区的巨型子弹蚁，其叮咬在施氏刺痛指数中排名最高
Giant tropical bullet ants ranked highest on the Schmidt pain index,
我不在的时候他们一直替我看着你呢
they're here to keep an eye on you when I can't.
皮娒博士正在楼下等你呢
Dr. Pym's waiting for you downstairs.
谁？
Who?
啊…嘿，嗯？
Ahhh...hey, um,
这是谁的睡衣啊？
whose pajamas are these?
我这要怎么办？
How am I supposed to do this?
好吧，一点一点来
All right, just one step at a time.
呃
Ugh.
我不踩你们，你们也别咬我，成么？
You don't bite me, I don't step on you, deal?
我也可以处理掉服务器，克罗斯根本不会发现
I could take down the servers and Cross wouldn't even know.
我们不需要这个人
We don't need this guy.
我猜你已经见过我女儿，霍普了
I assume that you've already met my daughter Hope.
见过了
I did.
她真不错
She's great.
她觉得我们不需要你
She doesn't think that we need you.
就是不需要，我们自己就能做
We don't. We can do this ourselves.
我做了一切努力让你能偷走我的衣服，结果霍普她
I go to all this effort to let you steal my suit, and then Hope
叫警察抓了你
has you arrested.
好吧，可以先试试，等他失败了我再自己做
Okay, we can try this and when he fails I'll do it myself.
她有点过于紧张了，这件事必须得做
She's a little bit anxious. It has to do with this job,
鉴于你已经坐在我对面了
which, judging by the fact that you're sitting opposite me,
我假设你算是感兴趣了
I take it that you're interested in.
是件什么事？
What job?
你要来点茶么？
Would you like some tea?
呃，好啊
Uh, sure.
你绕过我安保系统的方法给我留下来了很深的印象
I was very impressed with how you managed to get past my security system.
尤其是冷冻破环铁门那件事
Freezing that metal was particularly clever.
你那时候一直在监视我吗？
Were you watching me?
斯科特，我已经观察你有一阵子了
Scott, I've been watching you for a while,
从你抢了维斯塔公司之后就开始了
ever since you robbed Vista Corp.
哦，抱歉，“偷”了维斯塔公司
Oh, excuse me, burgled Vista Corp.
维斯塔的安保系统是业内非常先进的
Vista's security system is one of the most advanced in the business.
本应是无法被破坏的，可你却破坏了它
It's supposed to be unbeatable but you beat it.
要不要来点糖？
Would you like some sugar?
嗯，谢啦
Yeah, thanks.
呃，还是不用了…
You know what, I'm okay.
你是怎么让它们做到这些的？
How do you make them do that?
蚂蚁可以举起50倍于他们自身重量的物体
Ants can lift objects fifty times their weight.
他们可以互相合作，建造，养殖…
They build, farm, they cooperate with each other.
是，可是，这个，怎么做到的？
Right. But how do you make them do that?
用电磁波呀，模拟他们的嗅觉神经信号
I use electromagnetic waves, to stimulate their olfactory nerve center.
就可以和他们讲话了
I speak to them.
我可以到任何地方，听见和看见任何事情
I can go anywhere, hear anything, and see everything.
但你依然什么都不明白
And still know absolutely nothing.
要来不及了，我得去见克罗斯了
I'm late to meet Cross.
呃……皮娒博士？
Uh...Dr. Pym?
斯科特，你提问题时不用举手
You don't need to raise your hand, Scott.
抱歉，我只有一个问题
Sorry, I just have one question.
你到底谁啊她又是谁啊这都是什么鬼东西我现在能回监狱去吗？
Who are you who is she what the hell's going on and can I go back to jail now?
跟我来
Come with me.
20年前，我创造了一个方程式，可以改变原子间的距离
Twenty years ago I created a formula that altered atomic relative distance.
啊？
Huh?
我掌握了改变原子间距的技术，那件制服就是这个原理
I learned how to change the distance between atoms, that's what powers the suit,
所以它才可以这样
that's why it works.
哇哦！
Wow!
- 哇哦！ - 但这也很危险
- Whoa. - But it was dangerous.
因为太危险了
It was too dangerous.
所以我才把它藏了起来
So I hid it from the world.
也就是那时候，我改变了方向，创造了我的公司
And that's when I switched gears and I started my own company.
皮娒科技
Pym Tech.
是
Yes.
我收了个叫做达伦·克罗斯的徒弟
I took on a young protege called Darren Cross.
达伦·克罗斯，他可有名了
Darren Cross. He's a big deal.
在他出名以前，他只是我的助手
But before he was a big deal he was my assistant.
我以为我从他身上看到了什么，也许很像是我从没有过的儿子
I thought I saw something in him, a son I never had perhaps.
他是个天才，但是随着我们的关系越来越亲密
He was brilliant, but as we became close he began to suspect
他开始怀疑我并没有告诉他一切
that I wasn't telling him everything.
他听到了一些关于皮娒粒子的传言
He heard rumors about what was called the Pym Particle,
之后就一直痴迷于复制我的公式
and he became obsessed with recreating my formula.
我不想帮他，所以他就与人串通针对我
But I wouldn't help him so he conspired against me and
投票把我从我的公司踢了出来
he voted me out of my own company.
他是怎么做到的？
How could he do that?
董事会主席是我的女儿，霍普
The board's chairman is my daughter, Hope.
是她投出了那关键一票
She was the deciding vote.
但在发现克罗斯几乎成功破解我的方程后，她回到我身边了。
But she came back to me when she saw how close Cross was to cracking my formula.
这个过程是非常不稳定的
The process is highly volatile.
如果没有使用特殊的头盔防护
What isn't protected by a specialized helmet
将会直接影响脑部的化学反应
can affect the brain's chemistry.
我觉得达伦并没有意识到这一点，况且，他也没有那么稳重能想到这里
I don't think Darren realizes this, and y'know, he's not the most stable guy to begin with.
那么，你想要我做什么呢
So, what do you want from me?
斯科特，我相信每个人都应该得到一个救赎的机会
Scott, I believe that everyone deserves a shot at redemption.
你怎么看
Do you?
我也相信
I do.
如果这次你能帮我，我就答应帮你处理你女儿的事情
If you can help me, I promise I can help you be with your daughter again.
你准备好拯救你自己了吗？
Now are you ready to redeem yourself?
完全准备好了
Absolutely.
我洗心革面了，以后再也不干溜进去偷东西那种烂事了。
My days of breaking into places and stealing shit are done.
你想让我做什么？
What do you want me to do?
我想让你溜进个地方偷点东西
I want you to break into a place and steal some shit.
你晚上在家吃饭吗？
You going to be home for dinner tonight?
（朗的律师就是汉克·皮娒博士，皮娒科技的那个）
嗯，在，我出去办点事
Uh, yeah. I'll pick something up, okay?
去吧
Okay.
有什么好事么
Good news?
我不确定是不是件好事
Uh, I don't know. It's news.
你是要去找我爸爸吧？
Are you trying to find my daddy?
呃，是的，小甜心
Yeah, I am, sweetheart.
我只是希望你爸爸能安全
I just want your daddy to be safe.
我希望你不要抓他
Hope you don't catch him.
这已经不是第一次他们试图获取那种可以
This isn't the first time these guys have tried to get their hands
改变游戏规则的武器了
on game changing weaponry.
他是米切尔·卡森，神盾局的前任防御负责人
That's Mitchell Carson, ex-head of defense at SHIELD,
现在跑去做反政府的行当了
presently in the business of toppling governments.
她一直想要我的技术
He always wanted my tech.
所以除非我们能溜进去，偷走黄蜂装甲
And now, unless we break in and steal the Yellowjacket
并且销毁所有数据
and destroy all the data,
否则达伦·克罗斯已经会给这个世界带来混乱的
Darren Cross is gonna unleash chaos upon the world.
我觉得，我们不是应该先通知复仇者的吗…？
I think our first move should be calling the Avengers.
我花了半辈子的时间，就为了不让斯塔克得到这项技术
I've spent half my life trying to keep this technology out of the hands of a Stark.
所以我是死也不会交给他们的
I'm sure as hell not going to hand-deliver it to one now.
这可不像是钢铁侠那种可爱小粉红
This is not some cute technology like the Iron Man suit.
这可是会对现实世界产生巨大影响的
This could change the texture of reality.
另外他们现在大概正忙着把城市从天上摔下来玩呢（复联2）
Besides they're probably too busy dropping cities out of the sky.
好吧，那你不能送那些蚂蚁去办吗？
Okay, then why don't you just send the ants?
斯考特，他们只是蚂蚁
Scott, they are ants.
他们的确可以办很多事，但也是需要一个人指挥的
Ants, they can do a lot of things, but they still need a leader.
比如有些可以侵入那些专门设计成不可侵入的地方的人
Somebody that can infiltrate a place that's designed to prevent infiltration.
汉克，我就是个贼，好吧，是个很棒的贼
Hank, I'm a thief. All right, I'm a good thief.
但是这太疯狂了
But this is insane.
他说的对汉克，你知道的
He's right Hank and you know it.
你都已经看见了，你知道克罗斯能干出什么事来
You've seen the footage, you know what Cross is capable of.
如果我们还有几个月的时间我也不会用他，可是我们就剩几天了
I was against using him when we had months, now we have days.
我来穿那件制服
I'm wearing the suit.
绝对不行
Absolutely not!
我熟悉那里的一切，克罗斯怎么想我也清楚
I know the facility inside and out. I know how Cross thinks.
没有人能比我更适合这个任务了
I know this mission better than anybody here.
我们需要你接近克罗斯，不然这计划是行不通的
We need you close to Cross otherwise this mission cannot work.
- 我们没时间浪费了 - 霍普，请你听我说，求你了
- We don't have time to screw around. - Hope, please, listen to me, please.
他是个罪犯，我是你女儿！
He is a criminal. I'm your daughter.
不行！
NO!
她说的对，汉克
She's right, Hank.
我的确不合适
I'm not your guy.
为什么你自己不穿那件制服呢
Why don't you wear the suit?
你以为我不想吗
You think I don't want to?
我不能
I can't.
我穿了太多年了
I spent years wearing it.
这让我付出了代价
It took a toll on me.
你是我们唯一的选择了
You're our only option.
在霍普失去她妈妈之前，她一直把我
Before Hope lost her mother, she used to look at me like
当作是世界上最伟大的人
I was the greatest man in the world.
可是现在她看我的眼神中只有失望
And now she looks at me and it's just disappointment.
对我来说已经太迟了
It's too late for me.
但你不是
But not for you.
这是你的机会
This is your chance.
一个重新变回你女儿心目中英雄的机会
The chance to earn that look in your daughter's eyes.
变回她心底一直坚信的那个英雄
To become the hero that she already thinks you are.
这并不是为了拯救我们生活的这个世界
It's not about saving our world.
这是为了拯救她们心中的那个世界
It's about saving theirs.
哇塞，你说的真是太感人了
Damn, that was a good speech.
斯科特
Scott.
我需要你成为蚁人
I need you to be the Ant-Man.
如果使用正确的话，制服与穿戴者是共生的
In the right hands, the relationship between man and suit is symbiotic.
制服具有力量，而穿戴者可以驾驭力量
The suit has power, the man harnesses that power.
你要有技巧，足够灵敏，而想要做到这些
You need to be skillful, agile, and above all,
你得够快
you need to be fast.
你得能在很短的时间内缩小或者还原体型
You should be able to shrink and grow on a dime, so
这样才能发挥体型的优势
your size always suits your needs.
现在，从钥匙孔里钻过来，斯科特
Now dive through the keyhole, Scott.
保持正常体型冲刺，缩小钻过去
You charge big, you dive small,
然后再马上恢复正常
then you emerge big.
嗷！
Ow!
啊！
Ah!
噢
Ow.
真没用
Useless.
当你变小的时候，你的力量也被集中了
When you're small energy is compressed
你依然有成年男人的力量
so you have the force of a 200 pound man
并可以将其集中在百分之一英寸的点上
behind a fist a 100th of an inch wide
你就像个子弹一样
you're like a bullet.
如果出拳太重，你会把人杀死
You punch too hard, you kill someone,
太轻，又完全没有用
too soft, it's a love-tap.
换句话说，你得学会怎么出拳
In other words you have to know how to punch.
我在监狱里呆了三年呢，我当然知道怎么出拳
I was in prison for three years, I know how to punch.
打一个看看
Show me.
- 太烂了 - 那你来一个给我瞧瞧
- Terrible. - You want to show me how to punch?
让我看…
Show me-
这才叫一拳
That's how you punch.
- 她就等着这个呢 - 咱不开玩笑
- She's been looking forward to this. - No kiddin'.
霍普在…呃…那件事之后参加过格斗训练
Hope trained in martial arts at a, uh, difficult time.
哦，说到那件事，他指的是在我妈妈死后
Oh, by difficult time, he means when my mother died.
她死于一次坠机事故
We lost her in a plane crash.
你不告诉我她的死因就已经够了，能别再编故事了吗？
It's bad enough you won't tell me how she died, could you please stop telling me that lie.
我们现在有正经事办
We're working here.
行了小公主，起来干活了
All right princess, let's get back to work.
你那是手吗？！
Were you going for the hand?
你知道么，我觉得这个控制器很碍事
You know, I think this regulator is holding me back.
别动那个控制器
Do not screw with the regulator.
如果那个控制器坏掉了，你会进入亚原子态
If that regulator is compromised you would go sub-atomic.
那是啥意思？
What does that mean?
就是说你会进入量子空间领域
It means that you would enter a quantum realm.
那又是啥意思？
What does that mean?
就是说你会不断的缩小，你会进入一个现实中的时间
It means that you would enter a reality where all concepts of time and space
与空间概念都会变得与你永远无关的世界
become irrelevant as you shrink for all eternity.
你所知道的一切
Everything that you know,
所爱的一切
and love,
都会永远消失
gone forever.
哇，太酷了，我是说…如果他不坏的话
Cool. Yeah. I'm- If it ain't broke.
关于制服你已经学的差不多了，现在你该学学关于你那些厉害的盟友了
You've learned about the suit, but you've yet to learn about your greatest allies
蚂蚁们
the ants.
他们忠诚，勇敢，同时也是你的搭档
Loyal, brave, and your partners on this job.
长角立毛蚁，也叫狂蚁
Paratrechina longicornis, commonly known as crazy ants,
他们速度极快，同时还可以导电
they're lightning fast and can conduct electricity
可以用来烤烂敌人的电子设备
which makes them useful to fry out enemy electronics.
你看起来不怎么疯狂呀
Oh you're not so crazy.
嘿！
Hey!
你真可爱
You're cute.
哦，啊啊啊阿！
Oh! Aaah!
刚才那一秒真的特别吓人
That was a lot scarier a second ago.
啊啊啊阿！
Aaah!
这个炫酷实验室应该是有个独立的电源
It looks like the Futures lab has its own isolated power supply.
这里有保安昼夜不停的站岗
There's a security guard posted around the clock, we need you
我们需要你把他引开来解除安保系统
to take him out to deactivate the security systems.
好的
Okay.
下一个
Who's next?
Paraponera clavata（子弹蚁）
Paraponera clavata.
哈，我知道那个，就是子弹蚁，你说过
I know. Bullet ants, right?
施氏刺痛指数第一名的那个
Number one on the Schmidt pain index.
你们好呀
Hey guys!
还记得我吗，卧室里的那个
Remember me from the bedroom?
噢噢噢噢！
Whoa!
黄蜂装甲存放在一个密不透风的存储舱中
The Yellowjacket pod is hermetically sealed
唯一能够入侵的通道是一个5毫米宽的管道
and the only access point is a tube we estimate to be about 5 millimeters in diameter.
我突然觉得有点恶心
Why do I have a sick feeling in my stomach?
那个管道设有激光网防护，我们只能把电源切断
The tube is protected by a laser grid and we can only power that down
大概15秒钟
for fifteen seconds.
你需要控制狂蚁去烧掉服务器，拿到装甲
You're going to need to signal the crazy ants to blow the servers,
然后在后备电源启动前逃出那个存储舱
retrieve the suit, and exit the vaults, before the backup power comes on.
宾夕法尼亚弓背蚁
Camponotus pennsylvanicus.
也可以叫它黑木蚁
Alternatively known as a carpenter ant.
是理想的陆空交通工具
Ideal for ground and air transport.
等一下，我认识他
Wait a minute, I know this guy.
我要给他起名叫安东尼
I'm going to call him Antony.
呃，很好，非常好
That's good, that's, that's very good
因为这次
because this time
你得学会怎么自己控制他了
you're really going to have to learn how to control him.
让他们把糖块放到茶杯里
Tell them to put the sugar in the teacup.
哦，打疼你了吗，霍…
Oh, you okay Dr.-
啊！
Ah!
嗷！
Ah!!
汉克叫你出去做投掷训练
Hank wants you outside for target practice.
这制服本身是没有武器的，所以我给你做了这些飞盘
The suit has no weapons so I made you these discs.
红色的可以缩小
Red shrinks.
而蓝色的可以放大
Blue enlarges.
火蚁
Solenopsis mandibularis.
被叮刺后会有灼烧感因而得名，同时也是杰出的建筑师
Known for their bite, the fire ants have evolved into remarkable architects.
他们有能力带你进出很多地方
They are handy to get you in and out of difficult places.
你能做到的，斯科特
You can do it Scott, come on.
他们根本不听我的
They're not listening to me.
你得是发自内心的，集中精神的想
You have to commit, you have to mean it.
别老想着走捷径，也不要撒谎
No shortcuts, no lies.
你也不用老是骂他啊，这没有任何帮助，霍普
Throwing insults into the mix will not do anyone any good, Hope.
我可没功夫宠着他
We don't have time for coddling.
我们现在的重点是要帮助斯科特
Our focus should be on helping Scott.
是么？
Really?
这就是我们的重点咯？
Is that where our focus should be?
霍普！
Hope!
我真不知道为什么一开始会找上你
I don't know why I came to you in the first place.
没有她我们根本做不到
We can't do this without her.
我的天哪
Oh God.
你可得锁好门
You gotta lock your doors.
我说真的
I mean, really.
这附近有不少奇怪的家伙呢
There's some weird folks in this neighborhood.
你觉得这很好笑么？
Do you think this is a joke?
你真的知道他让你冒着什么样的风险吗？
Do you have any idea what he's asking you to risk?
- 你有个女儿 - 我就是为了她才这么做的
- You have a daughter. - I'm doing this for her.
你知道么，我妈妈死后，他消失了整整两个礼拜
You know when my mother died I didn't see him for two weeks?
他那时很悲痛
He was in grief.
我也悲痛啊，我才七岁啊
Yeah, so was I, and I was seven.
然后他再也没回来过，原本的那个人也不见了
And he never came back, not in any way that counted.
他就这么把我送进了寄宿学校
He just sent me off to boarding school.
你知道么，有时候我觉得
You know, I thought,
在这种危急关头的时候
with all that's at stake,
也许，我们能够借机和好如初
just maybe we might have a chance of making peace.
但直到现在他一直都把我排除在外
But even now he still wants to shut me out.
他并不想把你排除在外啊
He doesn't want to shut you out.
- 他信任你 - 那为什么你会在这儿
- He trusts you. - Then why are you here?
这恰恰证明了他爱你
It proves that he loves you.
霍普，你听我说
Hope. Look at me.
我就是个炮灰啊
I'm expendable.
这就是为什么我在这儿
That's why I'm here.
你必须要明白这件事
You must've realized that by now.
我是说，这就是为什么我要去穿那件制服，而你不用
I mean, that's why I'm in the suit and you're not.
因为他宁可输掉这场战斗，也不愿意失去你啊
He'd rather lose this fight than lose you.
就是这样
Anyway.
其实，我当时叫警察抓你的时候并不知道你还有个女儿
You know, I didn't know you had a daughter when I called the cops on you.
她叫什么名字
What's her name?
凯茜
Cassie.
真是个好听的名字
It's a pretty name.
你得清空杂念，斯科特
You have to clear your mind, Scott.
你得精确地表达你的想法，这样才能行
You have to make your thoughts precise, that's how it works.
想想凯茜吧
Think about Cassie,
想想你有多希望能见到她，就像那种程度一样
about how badly you want to see her, and use that to focus.
然后睁开眼睛，脑子里去想你要让蚂蚁们做的事
Open your eyes and just think about what you want the ants to do.
非常棒
That's good.
你妈妈说服了我让她加入任务
Your mother convinced me to let her join me on my missions.
他们叫她黄蜂女
They called her the Wasp.
她简直就是天生的
She was born to it.
可是往后的日子里，我每天都在后悔当初为什么答应她
And there's not a day that goes by that I don't regret having said yes.
那是在1987年
It was 1987.
一批分裂分子在库尔斯克劫持了一个苏联的导弹发射井
Separatists had hijacked a Soviet missile silo in Kursk
然后往美国发射了一枚洲际弹道导弹
and launched an ICBM at the United States.
能够进入导弹内部的唯一方法
The only way to the internal mechanics
就是穿过坚固的钛金属
was through solid titanium.
我知道我必须要缩小到可以通过分子间隙才能关掉导弹
I knew I had to shrink between the molecules to disarm the missile,
但是我的控制器被损坏的很严重
but my regulator had sustained too much damage.
你妈妈她一点都没有犹豫
Your mother, she didn't hesitate.
珍妮特！不！！！
Janet! No!!!
她关掉了她的控制器
She turned off her regulator
进入了亚原子态
and went sub-atomic
然后关掉了那个炸弹
to deactivate the bomb.
她就这么走了
She was gone.
你妈妈是像英雄一样死去的
Your mom died a hero.
之后的十年里，我竭尽了全力
And I spent the next ten years trying to learn all I could
去了解关于量子领域的一切
about the quantum realm.
你想要把她救回来
You were trying to bring her back.
但我得到的唯一结论，就是我们什么都不知道
But all I learned was we know nothing.
这不是你的错
It's not your fault.
她做出了她的选择
She made her choice.
可是你为什么不早点告诉我这一切？
But why didn't you tell me this sooner?
我只想要去保护你
I was trying to protect you.
我已经失去了你的母亲
I lost your mother.
我不想连你也一起失去
I didn't mean to lose you too.
我真的很抱歉
I'm sorry.
这真是太酷了
This is awesome.
太酷了，你们看
It's awesome. Y'know.
你们终于放下心结，平复了内心的创伤
You guys are breaking down walls, you're healing.
这是很重要的
It's important.
我把气氛全给毁了是吧
I ruined the moment didn't I.
完全的，你也知道啊
Yes, you did, yes.
那我还是去泡点茶好了
I'm going to make some tea.
搞定！
Nailed it!
你真是个好孩子，安东尼
That's a good boy, Antony.
训练的最后一步是要教你怎样隐身侵入
The final phase of your training will be a stealth incursion.
冻死我了！
It's freezing!
你就不能加个法兰绒的里衬吗
You couldn't make a simple flannel lining?
我们必须得取回那个信号干扰器的原型机
We must retrieve this prototype of a signal decoy,
那是我还在神盾局的时候发明的一个装置
it's a device that I invented during my SHIELD days.
我们需要用它去抵消那些克罗斯装在厂房里的信号阻断装置
We need it to counteract the transmission blockers that Cross installed in the Futures vault.
那东西现在应该封存在霍华德·斯塔克的一个旧仓库里
It's currently collecting dust in one of Howard Stark's old storage facilities
位于纽约的北部
in upstate New York.
应该是小菜一碟
Should be a piece of cake.
你已经到达目标上空了
You're over the target area.
现在就解除连接，斯科特
Disengage, now, Scott.
A小分队，出动
Squadron A, go.
B小分队，出动
B, go.
C小分队，出动
C, go.
好了，安东尼，这次可别再把我扔下去了
All right, Antony, please don't drop me this time.
从方糖块儿到这个，感觉真是一个巨大的飞跃呢
Ah, it feels like a big leap from sugar cubes to this.
冷静
Stay calm.
额，各位，我们可能有麻烦
Uh, guys, we might have a problem.
汉克，你不是说只是个旧仓库吗
Hank, didn't you say this was some old warehouse?
根本不是啊
It's not!
你这个老伙计
You son of a bitch!
- 斯科特，快离开那里 - 终止行动！马上！
- Scott, get out of there. - Abort! Abort now.
不，没事，看起来这里并没有人啊
No, it's okay. It doesn't look like anyone's home.
安东尼，带我到屋顶上去
Antony, get me to the roof.
他会把制服搞丢的
He's gonna lose the suit.
他会没命的！
He's gonna lose his life.
好啦，我现在在目标建筑的屋顶上了
All right I'm on the roof of the target building.
有人来了，斯科特
Somebody's home, Scott.
那里出什么事了，萨姆
What's going on down there, Sam?
是猎鹰！
It's the Falcon!
有警报被触发了，可我什么也没发现
I had a sensor trip but I'm not seeing anything.
等一下
Wait a second.
放弃，斯科特，马上终止行动
Abort Scott, abort now.
没事拉，他看不见我
It's okay. He can't see me.
我看见你了
I can see you.
他看得见我
He can see me.
嗨，我是斯科特
Hi. I'm Scott.
他刚说“嗨我是斯科特”了？！
Did he just say "Hi I'm Scott?"
你在这里干什么
What are you doing here?
首先，
First off,
我是你的超级粉丝
I'm a big fan.
谢了，那么你到底是谁啊？
'Preciate it. So who the hell are you?
我是蚁人
I'm Ant-Man.
蚁人？
Ant-Man?
啥？你没听说过我吗？
What, you haven't heard of me?
好吧你应该是没听说过
Nah, you wouldn't have heard of me.
你准备告诉我你要来干什么吗？
You want to tell me what you want?
我是想来拿走一样高科技的
I was hoping I could grab a piece of technology
就用几天，然后就还回来
just for a few days, I'm gonna return it.
我需要用它拯救世界，你懂我的意思
I need it to save the world. You know how that is.
别跟我扯拯救世界
I know exactly how that is.
定位入侵者位置，送他进去
Located the breach. Bringing him in.
我很抱歉要这么做
Sorry about this.
你这是想要干什么啊？
What the hell are you doing?
入侵者是一名成年男子，他具有某种缩小的技术
Breach is an adult male who has some sort of shrinking tech.
对不起
Sorry.
听着，我真的很抱歉这么做，对不起
Look, I'm sorry about this, sorry.
够了！
That's enough!
安东尼，帮我下
Antony, a little help.
我没有影像了
I've lost visual.
他在我的背包里
He's inside my pack.
抱歉
Sorry.
你真的是个好人
You seem like a really great guy.
请千万不要告诉队长这件事，这对我很重要
It's really important to me that Cap never finds out about this.
那是完全不负责任的，危险的行为
That was completely irresponsible and dangerous.
你破坏了整个行动
You jeopardized everything.
你拿到它了
You got it.
干得不错
Well done.
等等，你刚刚是夸我了吗？
Wait a minute. Did you just compliment me?
他夸我了，对不对？
He did, didn't he?
听起来像是那么回事
Kinda sounded like he did.
我很棒的，是不是
I was good, wasn't I?
那我呢，我跟一个复仇者打了一架，而且还没死
Hey, how about the fact that I fought an Avenger, and didn't die?
别沉浸在这件事上了
Now let's not dwell on the past.
我们还有计划要完成
We gotta finish our planning.
别理他
Don't mind him.
你做的很好
You did good.
达伦！
Darren!
你怎么跑进来了
How the hell'd you get in here?
你忘关家门了啊，汉克
You left the front door open, Hank.
看来没错，你老了
It's official. You're old.
那个计划！
The plans!
他会杀了他的
He will kill him.
是什么风把你吹来了
Well to what do I owe this pleasure?
我有个好消息
I have good news.
是吗？
Really?
什么好消息？
What's that?
皮娒科技
Pym Tech,
你创建这个的公司
the company you created,
就要成为世界上最挣钱的企业之一了
is about to become one of the most profitable operations in the world.
我们预计仅明天就能签下价值150亿的订单
We're anticipating 15 billion in sales tomorrow alone.
不用谢我
You're welcome.
我知道这听起来很奇怪，但我希望你能在场
I know this is odd, but I'd like you to be there.
这是我的时刻，我想让你看见
This is my moment, I want you to see it.
当然了，达伦，是的，一定
Sure, Darren. Yeah, sure.
我会去的
I'll be there.
你看上我哪一点了？
What did you see in me?
我不明白你的意思
I don't know what you mean.
那么多年前，你选上了我
All those years ago, you picked me.
你从我身上看到什么了？
What did you see?
我看到了我自己
I saw myself.
那你为什么又将我拒之门外呢？
Then why did you push me away?
因为我看到了太多的我自己
Because I saw too much of myself.
他都知道了，他是在逗你上钩，我们得停止行动
He knows, he's baiting you. We have to call it off.
一切都有风险
We're all taking risks.
如果他看见我在这儿可怎么办
What if he saw me here?
他没看见你，不可能的
He didn't. There's no way.
你怎么知道不可能
How do you know that?
达伦，嘿
Darren, hi.
霍普
Hope.
你现在在哪呢
Where are you right now?
我在家呢，怎么啦？
I'm at home, why?
我刚去见了汉克
I just saw Hank.
他还是那样只会鄙视我
I still get nothing but contempt from him.
不要让他激怒你，他只是…只是个年迈的老人
Don't let him rile you up, he's just... he's a senile old man.
我们需要让所有人进入状态了
We need to start everyone working around the clock,
启动生产线并开始运行
get the assembly line up and running.
同时我要大幅加强安保
And I'm tripling security.
在所有入口设置探测器，外部空气通风口都要安装钢微孔筛网
Full sensors at all entrances, and exterior air vents fitted with steel micro mesh.
很好，好主意
Great. Good idea.
谢谢你，霍普
Thank you, hope.
我很幸运能有你站在我这边
I'm so lucky to have you on my team.
他要大幅加强安保，他已经失去理智了
He's tripling security, he's lost his mind,
他已经完全针对你了
and he's on to you.
但他还没有针对你
But he's not on to you.
他要在所有入口设立全身扫描安检，还关掉了所有通风口
He's adding full body scanners to all entrances and closing exterior vents.
我们要怎么把斯科特带进去？
How are we gonna get Scott inside?
主供水通道
The water main.
在主供水通道上是没法加装安保系统的
You can't add security to a water main.
水压太强了，但如果我们能想办法降低压力，我就可以进去
The pressure is too strong, but if we can decrease it, that's how I get in.
那得有人能接近建筑的主控室才能改变水压啊
Somebody would have to reach the building's control center to change the water pressure.
我是说，汉克和我会一直呆在克罗斯旁边，我们怎么可能办得到呢
I mean, Hank and I will be beside Cross, how are we supposed to do that?
所以我们要扩展队伍
So we expand our team.
要怎么做呢？
What do we need?
一个人冒充警卫做内应，关闭供水压力
A fake security guard on the inside to depressurize the water system,
另外一个得骇进主电源然后关掉激光网
somebody else to hack into the power supply and kill the laser grid,
最后还需要一个车手接应
and a getaway guy.
哦，不，不，不
No, no. No, no no.
不要那三个傻帽儿，绝对不行
Not those three wombats. No way.
谢谢您的咖啡，女士
Thank you for the coffee ma'am.
通常如果回到作案现场的话
It's not too often that you rob a place,
是不太会受到欢迎的
and then get welcomed back.
可是你在招待我们耶！
Because we just robbed you!
你知道他是因为偷刨冰机才被关起来的，对吧？
You know that he was arrested for stealing a smoothie machine, right?
我偷了两台刨冰机
Two smoothie machines.
你确定他们能行么？
Are you sure they can handle this?
哦，我们肯定行，我们可专业了。
Oh we can handle it. We're professionals.
请原谅我们并没有对此充满信心
You'll forgive us if we're not instilled with confidence.
等等，大家先不要激动啊，各位
Wait, everybody, just kick back and relax a little bit, man,
我们很熟悉业务的
we know our business.
连这间高科技住宅我们都溜进来了不是吗
We broke into this spooky-ass house, didn't we?
那是因为我让你进来的
I let you.
我也可以说是我让你让我嘛
Well, one could say that I let you let me.
各位，可以了，他们能行的
Look, it's okay. They can handle this.
可不是，我们能行的
Yeah, we can handle it.
你搞定他们的身份信息了吗？
You got their credentials?
他已经在系统里了
He's in the system.
我在系统里了？
I'm in the system?
在系统里啦！
You're in the system!
系统耶！
The system?
得了，我们算是完蛋了
Yeah. We're doomed.
好了，有件事我得先让你们看看
All right, there's something you guys need to see.
当你走到这里时，在你的左侧会有三个办公室
When you get to this corner, there's gonna be three offices on your left side.
我靠！
Damn!
哇哦！这很酷啊，哥们儿！
Whoa! That's so cool, bro!
好了听着
Now look,
接下来会有些诡异了，可能会有点吓人，但绝对安全
this is gonna get weird, all right. It's pretty freaky but it's safe.
你们完全不用害怕
There's no reason to be scared.
呵，哥我啥都不怕
Aw, no no daddy don't get scared.
是么？
Really?
当然了
Yeah.
太好了
Good.
喔！
Oh!
这…这是那种…吉普赛人用的
This is the work of the gypsies.
这是，这是巫术！
That's, that's, that's witchcraft.
哇，太神奇了
Oh, that's amazing.
简直就是大卫·科波菲尔搞的那套
That's like some David Copperfield shit.
- 这肯定是某种巫术 - 用…用的魔法！
- That's some kind of wizardry. - Sorcery!
你是怎么做到的，兄弟？
How'd you do that bro?
别崩溃，往你肩膀上看
Don't freak out. Look at your shoulder.
啊啊啊！啊啊啊！下去！下去！快走！走！
Ahh!!  Ahh!!! Get off!  Get off, go go...
你不是说“哥我啥都不怕”的吗！
Wait, I thought daddy didn't get scared?
我给他们一人吃了半片安定，然后汉克开始解释制服的工作原理
I gave them each half a Xanax and Hank explained the science of the suit to them.
立刻就全睡过去了
Fell right asleep.
嘿，听着，我想谢谢你为了…
Hey, look. I want to thank you for-
别，不要谢我
No, please don't.
我们这样做都是为了那个更伟大的目标，这和个人无关
We're all doing this for reasons much bigger than any one of us.
我只是很高兴你能为整个计划贡献那一点点的力量
I'm just glad that you might have a slight chance of maybe pulling this off.
哈哈，谢谢你，为了
Hey. Thank you, you know,
为了你给我的那些鼓励
for that pep talk.
而事实真相就是，我已经从一开始的鄙视你，变得现在甚至有点喜欢你了呢
You know, the honest truth is I actually went from despising you to almost liking you.
你真应该去写鸡汤文
You really should write poetry.
早点休息吧，斯科特
Get some sleep Scott.
好啦，都准备好了，大家都知道自己应该干什么吧？
All right, just so we're clear, everyone here knows their role, right?
戴夫？
Dave?
车交给我了
Wheels on the ground.
科特？
Kurt?
情报交给我了
Eyes in the sky.
阿毛？
Luis?
噢，伙计，你懂的，哥我这就去找件制服穿上
Aw, man, you know it, you know what, I get to wear a uniform,
就这么定了
that's what's up.
阿毛！
Luis.
对不起，我错了，我知道该干什么就是有点兴奋，而且
I'm sorry, I mean, I'm good, I'm good, I'm just excited, and plus
你女朋友实在是太正点了，有美女在旁边我就紧张
you're girlfriend's really hot, so you know that makes me nervous too,
您真的好漂亮，女士
and you are very beautiful ma'am.
我的天哪
Oh my lord.
她并不是我的女…
She's not my-
嘿，还有，我觉得既然我要去当卧底了，我得想点计策
Hey, you know what, I was thinking of a tactic, like when I go undercover,
比如吹个口哨什么的，可以让我的角色更真实什么的
like a whistling, y'know I' saying, to like, blend in.
不要，别吹口哨
No. Don't whistle.
吹什么口哨，你又不是去表演
No whistling, it's not the Andy Griffith Show.
不许吹口哨
No whistling.
一区一切正常
All clear in sector one.
往前走
Step up.
可以了
All clear.
我们到位了
We're set.
祝我好运吧
Wish me luck.
设备已经就绪了
Utilities online.
(whistling "It's a Small World")
嘿，你在这儿干嘛
Hey. What are you doing?
呃，头儿说让我检查这个地方，我在检查咯
Uh, boss-man said to secure the area, so, I'm securing.
我就是头儿
I'm the boss.
喔！
Oh!
这里是设备间第3…
Utilities work room 3-
水位正在下降中
Water level is dropping.
喔哦！
Whoa!
正在从排气管里出来
Coming up on extraction pipe.
我看到了
I see it!
好了，来吧，我得上到上面去
All right, come on, I gotta get up there,
就这样，就这样伙计们，好的
that's it, that's it guys, yes!
就这样，好
That's it, yeah...
好极了，你们做到了
Yes! You got it!
真是太棒了，加油
You got it, come on!
好的，安东尼，我们起飞吧
All right, let's fly Antony.
蚁人已经成功入侵了
The Ant-Man is in the building.
嘘！前面那儿有辆福特皇冠
Pshhh. Got a Crown Vic right outside a'heah.
所以有什么问题么？
This is problem?
你不知道开福特皇冠基本都是警察卧底吗？
Considering that Crown Vics are the most commonly used car for under-cover cops, man,
嗯，的确是个问题
yes, this is a problem.
是皮姆
It's Pym.
哦，不
Oh, no.
我准备派子弹蚁出动了
I'm deploying the bullet ants.
（他是想说Paraponera clavata也就是子弹蚁的拉丁名）
哈帕内拉克莱那…玛莱那…玛…
Hapanera-clairna-mairna-mairna.
（他是想说Paraponera clavata也就是子弹蚁的拉丁名）
虽然学名是怎么拼我给忘了，但我确定下面这位要倒大霉了
I don't remember what it's called but I feel bad for this guy.
嘿，你好吗
What's up man.
嗷！嗷！！
Ow! Ow!!
看，这就是我说过的那种，我管这叫一个不幸的意外
See, that's what I'm talkin' bout, that's what I call it, an unfortunate casualty,
在一个很正经的行动中的…
in a very serious operation.
信号干扰器已就位
Signal decoy in place.
恶毒美女干得不错嘛，斯科特
Mean pretty lady did good, Scott.
看起来警察好像要抓皮姆
Looks like Pym's getting arrested.
斯科特，我们有麻烦了
Scott, we have problem.
麻烦？有什么麻烦？
Problem? What's the problem?
戴夫！戴夫，我们不是那么计划的！
Dave! Dave, that's not part of plan!
听我说
Listen to me.
如果你们不让我进去，会有很多人因此死掉的
If I don't get into this building people will die.
这个故事编的太差劲了
That's awfully dramatic.
你玩儿我呢吗？
Are you kidding me?
蛤蛤蛤！
Ha ha ha!
问题解决了
Problem solved.
好吧
Well.
我看起来如何？
How do I look?
在这儿呢
There he is.
时间刚好
Just in time.
来吧
Come on.
十二处验证中
Twelve point verification.
有点夸张了吧，不是么达伦
Little over the top, don't you think Darren?
确认授权中
Confirming authorization.
安全永远第一吗
No you can never be too safe.
访问已允许
Access granted.
看来我可以把一切交给你了，达伦，你做的很棒
I gotta hand it to you, Darren, you really did it.
你只看到了一半而已，汉克
And you only know the half of it, Hank.
到达第二个目标点
Arriving at second position.
好的，全速前进安东尼，出发
All right, top speed, Antony. Let's go.
正在靠近最终目标处
Proceeding to command position.
我马上回来，安东尼
I'll be right back Antony.
好了伙计们，我到位了
All right guys, I'm in position.
我准备操控蚂蚁了
I'm going to signal the ants.
噢，不不不！
No no nooo.
你看见了吧？蛤蛤蛤蛤！
Did you see that? Ha ha ha, ha ha!
组成阵型
Assume formation.
好了，可爱的小疯子们
All right you cute little crazies,
烧了这些服务器吧
let's fry these servers.
现在去拿那个吧，伙计
Let's go get it buddy!
喔哈！
Whoo-haa!
服务器已经完了，所有数据备份都被清除了
Servers are fried. Data backup completely erased.
已经在去展示舱的路上了
Heading to the particle chamber.
你好，克罗斯博士
Hello Dr. Cross.
我的合伙人已经同意了你的条款
My associates have agreed to your terms.
太好了
Wonderful.
卡森先生向我介绍了这几位杰出的绅士
Mr. Carson introduced me to these fine gentlemen here,
他们是九头蛇的代表
they're representatives of Hydra.
他们和原来的已经不同了
They're not what they were.
现在正在做些很有意思的工作
They're doing some interesting work.
而我很享受这一刻
And I'm enjoying myself.
你一直不告诉我的你的那些技术，现在我就要全扔你脸上了
You tried to hide your technology from me, and now it's going to blow up in your face.
哇哦
Wow.
哇哦！
Wow!
我是说，我早就知道你会给我这一拳
I mean, I saw the punch coming a mile away
但我本以为会又弱又可怜呢
but I just figured it'd be all pathetic and weak.
那你是想错了
Well you figured wrong.
我见过这个货车
I know this van.
里面有人吗？
Anybody home?
- 嘘 - 嘘
- Shh. - Shh.
- 嘘！ - 嘘！
-Shh! -Shh!!
好了伙计们，我到了
All right guys I'm here.
炸药已经激活了
Setting the charges.
干的很棒各位，我就在这儿跟你们分手了
Great job guys. I'll take it from here.
好孩子，安东尼
Good boy Antony.
到达最终目标地点
Final position.
伙计们，那个激光网怎么样了？
Guys? How we lookin' on that laser grid?
- 差不多了 - 差得远呢
- Almost! - No you're not.
- 马上就好了！ - 根本不是
- I'm getting close! - No you're not.
旧金山警察局！里面的人听着！
San Francisco PD! Man in the van!
我知道你们在里面！
I know you're in there!
- 让它走快点 - 哥们，你是认真的吗？
- Make it go faster. - Dude. Seriously.
我准备跳了，你收到了吗科特
Ready to jump. Do you read Kurt?
就差一点了
So close.
- 别动！ - 是，等一下，等一下
- Freeze! - Okay, wait a minute wait a minute,
刚刚有个和我特别像的黑人攻击了我们
there was a black guy that looked exactly like me who attacked us
然后把我们关在了这个恶心的货车里
and put us in the back of this disgusting van.
- 给我出来 - 哦，别这样
- Get out. - Take it easy!
现在去吧！
Go now!
- 等等！ - 什么？你说等等是什么意思？
- Wait! - What? What d'you mean wait?
什么？什么？
What? What?
嘿，我说
Hello guy.
我早就怀疑你在什么地方藏了一套制服
I always suspected you had a suit stored away somewhere,
那么现在的问题就是，这位新蚁人是谁呢？
which begs the question, who is the new Ant-Man?
我敬爱的导师比起我来更信任的这个人，是谁呢？
Who is the man that my beloved mentor trusted even more than me?
斯科特·朗
Scott Lang.
可怜的家伙
The martyr
他为他的行为付出了代价
who took on the system and paid the price,
家已经毁了，唯一的女儿也离他而去
losing his family and his only daughter in the process,
跟你还真是像啊，汉克
exactly your kind of guy, Hank.
他没有留下任何痕迹就从监狱中逃跑了
He escapes his jail cell without leaving any clue as to how,
然后呢
and then,
就这样直接消失了
he disappears magically,
连值多少钱都还不知道呢，他就把这件蚁人制服送来了
despite having no money to his name, and now he brings me the Ant-Man suit,
这个唯一可以和我的作品媲美的东西
the only thing that can rival my creation.
达伦，不要这么做
Darren, don't do this.
如果你卖给这些人，这个世界会变得一团糟的
If you sell to these men, it's going to be chaos.
我已经卖了，而且多亏了你，卖了双倍的价钱呢
I already have, and for twice the price, thanks to you.
能溜进复仇者的机构中可是不简单呢
It's not easy to successfully infiltrate an Avengers facility.
幸亏这件事儿传得快
Thankfully, word travels fast.
哦，我只卖给了他们黄蜂装甲，粒子我可没给他们
Oh I'll sell them the Yellowjacket but I'm keeping the particle to myself.
那可是装甲的燃料
They don't run on diesel.
如果想使用装甲，就得来找我买燃料哦
If you want the fuel you'll have to come to me.
如果一个人可以控制世界上最具有力量的武器的话，那他就是？
What do you call the only man who can arm the most powerful weapon in the world?
世界上最有力量的人
The most powerful man in the world.
你为我骄傲了吗？
You proud of me yet?
你可以阻止这一切的，达伦，现在还不晚
You can stop this, Darren. It's not too late.
这一刻已经来的太迟了
It's been too late for a long time now.
达伦
Darren.
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
他根本就没有能力照顾好你，就像对我一样
He wasn't any more capable of caring for you than he was for me.
这不是真正的你，你的思想已经被粒子影响了
This is not who you are. It's the particles altering your brain chemistry.
等下，等下，等一下
Wait, wait wait wait wait wait wait.
你说的太对了
You're right.
这才是我应该做的
I have to be the one to do it.
来吧咱们
Here we go.
把，枪，放，下
Drop. Your. Gun.
你知道么，那天晚上我本来是要去他家杀他的
You know I came to the house the other night to kill him
但不巧的是你也在
but you were there.
你病了，我可以帮助你，先把枪放下
You're sick and I can help you just put the gun down.
我那时候并没做好杀你的准备
I wasn't ready to kill you then.
但是现在我做好了
But I think I am now.
马上把枪放下！
Drop your gun now!
你站错队伍了，霍普
You picked the wrong side, Hope.
爸爸！
Dad!
汉克，哦，不，汉克
Hank. No, no. Hank.
汉克，听我说，你会没事的
Hank. Listen, you're gonna be okay.
好吗？你一定会没事的
All right, you're gonna be just fine.
把制服脱下来，不然我就先爆了你的头然后再扒它下来
Take the suit off or I'll blow your brains out and peel it off.
皮娒科技有情况，呼号10-33，请求支援
We got a 10-33 at Pym Tech, request immediate backup.
快走！快走！
Go, go, go.
送我到屋顶，准备好通讯
Get me to the roof and radio ahead.
我要直升机马上就能起飞
I want to make sure the helicopter's ready to take off.
你们俩，只要是从那里面出来的全部给我干掉
You two, kill anything that comes out of that vault.
爸爸
Dad,
你能动吗？
can you move?
我们得带他离开
We need to get him out of here.
去，拿，那件装甲
Go. Get. That suit.
嘿，斯科特
Hey Scotty.
我救了你没有啊？
Hey did I save your life?
斯科特？
Scotty?
谢啦阿毛
Thank you Luis.
我们现在是好人啦？
Hey are we the good guys?
- 是啊 - 我们真的当好人啦？
- Yeah. - We're the good guys right?
是的，我们是好人
Yeah, we're the good guys.
怎么，怎么感觉，感觉有点怪怪的
Feels kinda, kinda weird, y'know.
是么，可是还没完事儿呢
Yeah. But we're not done yet.
赶紧在这里爆炸之前逃出去
Get outta here before this place blows.
我了个去！
Oh, dammit!
那个人
That guy.
嘿！我们得出去啦
Hey! We're getting out of here.
炸弹已经激活了，我们得赶紧想办法逃出去
The charges are set. We've got to find a way out of here and fast.
别担心
Don't worry.
我还死不了
I'm not going to die.
你也不会
And neither are you.
这可不只是个钥匙链
It's not a keychain.
现场一片混乱
It's total chaos in here.
有很多处交火
Multiple shots fired.
还有一辆坦克…
And there's a tank.
帮我下
A little help.
我来吧
I got him.
我们需要医生
We need a doctor.
我们快走吧！
Let's go!
安东尼！
Antony!
快走！
Go!
你一定会后悔的
You're going to regret that.
等一下！都给我从那个货车上下来！
Wait a minute. Get out of that van.
- 啥？ - 马上给我下来！
- What? - Get out of that van.
坦克声太大，我没听清楚
It's too loud there's a tank I can't hear you.
嘿！嘿！！
Hey! Hey!
你疯了吗？快把枪放下！
Are you crazy? Put the gun down!
窗户！
The windows!
你以为抢走这个就能阻止这一切了吗？
Did you think you could stop the future with a heist?
谁告诉你我光要抢这个啦
It was never just a heist.
把枪放下
Put the gun down.
我看见他了，就在那里，快点，快快快
I got him, I got him, there he is, go go go go
我们得找地方降落
Got to set her down somewhere.
我会让你瓦解成碎片的！
I'm gonna disintegrate you!
正在播放治疗乐队的“瓦解”
Playing "Disintegration" by The Cure.
快报警！
Call 911!
没事儿啦
It's okay.
警察！举起手来！
Police! Put your hands up.
举起来！
Get 'em up.
斯科特？
Scott?
帕克斯顿
Paxton.
你得听我解…
You have to listen to me-
帕克斯顿，快掉头送我回去
Paxton. Turn around, take me back.
我是在送你回去，回监狱去
I am taking you back. To prison.
那个后院里有样东西必须要被摧毁
There's something in that backyard that needs to be destroyed.
在捕蚊灯里面，它…
In the bug zapper, it-
你还是断了这个念头吧！
You need to desist right now!
你的妄想已经一发不可收拾了！
Your delusions are out of hand!
所有单位注意，代号236，位于东街840号
All units we have a 236 in progress at 840 Winter Street.
是凯茜！
It's Cassie!
别害怕哦
Don't be scared.
帕克斯顿，让我来帮你
Paxton let me help.
- 你不许动 - 我想帮忙！
- Don't move. - Let me help!
玛姬，出什么事了
Maggie, what's going on?
- 他抓了凯茜！ - 谁抓了凯茜？
- He's got Cassie! - Who's got Cassie?
那个东西，那个，我不是到那是个什么…
That thing, that thing, I don't know what it...!
你是怪兽吗？
Are you a monster?
我看起来像怪兽吗？
Do I look like a monster?
我要找我爸爸！
I want my daddy.
我也想找你爸爸
I want your daddy too.
啊啊啊！
Aaaaah!
原来在这儿呢
There you are.
爸爸，是你吗？
Daddy, is that you?
嘿，小花生
Hi Peanut.
你倒是找个跟你一样大的打啊
Why don't you pick on someone your own size?
你想往哪藏呢，小家伙？
Now where'd you go, little guy?
抓到你了
There you are.
蛤蛤，蛤蛤
Ha ha ha ha.
可不只是我呢
Not just me.
我擦！
Dammit!
上！冲啊！
Go! Go!
斯科特需要我们，知道吗
Scotty needs us, y'know I' sayin'.
什么事也不能拦住我们
Ain't nothin' gonna stop us.
- 后退，慢慢地退 - 同意
- Back it up. Back it up slow. - Yeah.
- 后退 - 是呀
- Back it up. - Yep, yep.
- 后退 - 好的
- Back it up. - Okay.
我们只要慢慢地
All we gonna do is, we j-,
- 慢慢地后退就好了 - 说的太对了
- we just back it up. - Right, that's it.
- 后退 - 是呀
- Back it up. - That's right.
- 还要退 - 是
- Backin' up? - Yep.
- 那就慢慢地，慢慢地，后退吧
- Just back it, b-b-b- back it up.
你这是侮辱我，斯科特
You insult me, Scott.
你存在的本身就是在侮辱我
Your very existence is insulting to me.
如果你敢变大点，我一定会狠狠的揍死你
Y'know it would be much easier to hit you if you were bigger.
是啊，我也同意
Yeah, I agree.
凯茜！
Cassie!
我要让你明白，你有多么微不足道
I'm going to show you just how insignificant you are.
凯茜！我来了！
Cassie, I'm coming!
哇啊啊啊！
Waaaah!
这只狗怎么长成了这样
That's a messed-up looking dog.
我要摧毁你所爱的一切！
I'm going to destroy everything you love.
不许动！旧金山警察局！
Freeze! S.F.P.D.!
我没法进去
I can't break through.
这是钛金属，你这个白痴
It's titanium, you idiot.
快带她出去
Get her out of here.
走吧
Come on.
抱歉小宝贝
Sorry sweetheart.
你得替你爸爸弥补他犯下的错误
You have to help daddy pay for his mistakes.
- 躲在我身后，好吗？ - 好的
- You stay behind me, okay? - Okay.
在我身后
Behind me.
我得缩小到可以通过分子间距才能到达那里
I'm going to have to shrink between the molecules to get in there.
离我们远点！
Get away from us!
爸爸，救命！
Daddy, help!
我爱你凯茜
I love you Cassie.
啊啊啊！
Aaaaaaah!!!!
爸爸你在哪儿？
Daddy where are you?
你会进入亚原子态…
You could go sub-atomic...
亚原子态…
...go sub-atomic...
哦不
Oh no.
你会不断的缩小…你会进入一个现实中的时间与空间概念
You would enter a reality where all concepts of time and space (echos)
都变得…
become irrelevant. (echos continue)
与你永远…
And as you shrink...
无关的世界…
for all eternity...
你所知道的一切…
everything that you know...
所爱的一切…
and love...
都会永远消失
gone forever.
(Cassie's voice echos)
爸爸！
Daddy!
凯茜！
Cassie!
来啊爸爸
Come on daddy.
别乱动那个控制器
Do not mess with the regulator.
爸爸！
Daddy!
我真的好爱你
I love you so much.
我也爱你
I love you too.
真的
So much.
嗯…
Ahem.
屋顶被开了个大洞
There's a big hole in the roof.
抱歉
Sorry.
她没事吧？
Is she all right?
她没事
She's fine.
妈咪
Mommy.
她很好，她很好
She's fine, she's fine.
斯科特，说真的
Scott, please.
你什么都不记得了吗
You don't remember anything?
汉克，我真的…不记得了
Hank, I, I don't.
一定是有什么原因的
There must be something else.
但我猜大概凭人类是无法理解的吧，不过
Well I suppose the human mind just can't comprehend the experience, but
你做到了
you made it.
你去了那里
You went in
还成功回来了
and you got out.
真是太神奇了
It's amazing.
斯科特
Scott.
我陪你出去
I'll walk you out.
好好休息
Get some rest.
真的能做到吗？
Is it possible?
这又是怎么回事
When did this happen?
真的没事儿
Nothing's happening.
等等，明明是有点事儿
Well hold on. Something's kind of happening.
如果是这么回事儿的话，还是再给我一枪吧
Well if that's the case, uh, shoot me again.
嘿，你干嘛突然抓住我就开始亲啊
Yeah, I don't know what you're doing grabbing me and kissing me like that.
我都被吓蒙了，我还是先赶紧走吧
I was a little surprised myself. I have to get somewhere.
回头见汉克，你瞧瞧你，霍普
I'll see you later Hank. Really, Hope.
- 斯科特 - 嗯
- Scott. - Yeah.
- 你就是一坨屎 - 你说的太对了
- You're full of shit. - Oh yeah.
斯科特，我今天遇到我的队长了
Well Scott I met with my Captain today.
他要我给他个报告解释你是怎么出来的
He wanted a report of the night you got out of jail.
因为监控都出了点儿问题
Something happened with the cameras, and
电路也都故障了
circuits got fried, and...
但是我跟他说你是走正常程序出来的
But I told him you were processed correctly.
真的吗
Really?
是这样
Well yeah.
既然已经是技术故障了，我怎么还能把凯茜的爸爸抓起来呢？
Can't be sending Cassie's dad back to jail on a technical glitch, right?
谢谢你，帕克斯顿
Thank you Paxton.
我真是没想到
I'm blown away.
我也得谢谢你为了凯茜做的一切
Thank you for everything you do for Cassie.
哦，那是我应该做的
Oh well, that's my pleasure.
但不是因为这个，我是真心的想帮你的
But no, no this one, I, I did it for you.
呵呵，有点尴尬了
This is awkward.
- 是啊 - 是啊
- Yeah. - Yeah.
那我们是不是该聊点别的啥呢？
I mean what do we even talk about after all that?
- 哦我知道了 - 是什么呢？
- Oh I know. - What?
- 今天我头一次做了个侧手翻 - 不是吧！
- I did my first cartwheel today. - What?
是真的，她这礼拜一直在练习呢，今天终于成功了
Yeah. She has been practicing all week, but today was the magic day.
我用手机录下来了，看
I recorded it on my phone here.
不是吧，这不可能是凯茜呀，真是你吗？
No, that can't be Cassie. That's not you.
- 是真的 - 是真的
- Yeah it is. - Yeah it is.
这简直就是专业体操运动员呀，真的是你吗凯茜
This is a professional gymnast, there's no way that's her.
是她做的
Yeah, that's her.
好孩子
Good boy.
宝贝儿你真的了不起，真棒
Sweetie that's pretty amazing, Peanut.
抱歉
Sorry.
是工作的事儿
It's work.
什么？
Yeah?
好的
All right.
先说好了，直接告诉我是个什么事
Here's the deal. Just give me the facts.
就说事情本身，不要扯别的
Just the facts, only the facts.
吸气，集中
Breathe. Focus.
说重点
Keep it simple.
是是，当然了当然了
No no no, no doubt, no doubt.
就是那天吧，我跟我表弟伊格纳西奥去了艺术博物馆
Okay, so I'm at this art museum with my cousin Ignacio, right?
然后呢，那天博物馆里展览的主题应该是，叫什么抽象表现主义，你也知道我对吧
And there was this, like, abstract expressionism exhibit, and you know me, I'm more like
我比较喜欢的是新立体主义那种的
a Neo-cubist kind of guy, right?
可是那天展览的有罗斯科的作品，那个简直是太赞了，我的天哪…
（Marcus Rothkowitz，俄裔美国艺术家）
But there was this one Rothko that was sublime, bro, oh my God-
阿毛
Luis.
哦哦抱歉抱歉，我又跑…我一想到那个就特别兴奋
Okay sorry sorry I'm j- y'know uh, I just get excited and stuff.
总之，总之
But anyway, anyway.
伊格纳西奥跟我说：
Ignacio tells me:
哟，我昨天晚上遇到了个是记者的小妞，可棒了
Yo, I met this crazy fine writer chick at the spot last night, like,
简直了，特别，特别的正点
fine, fine, crazy stupid fine.
然后他去找了酒保聊了聊说
And he goes up to the bartender and goes:
看我带来的这姑娘，怎么样
Look at the girl I'm with? Y'know I' sayin'
超级正点的是不是
She's crazy stupid fine right?
然后酒保就说
And the bartender's all like:
嗯，的确正点
Yeah, crazy stupid fine.
然后那个记者小妞跟伊格纳西奥说：嘿你知道么
So this writer chick tells Ignacio: Yo, I'm like a boss in the world of
我也算八卦狗仔界里的一个人物，我可知道不少小道消息呢
guerrilla journalism, and I got mad connects with the peeps behind the curtains, y'know I' sayin?
伊格纳西奥就说：真的吗？
Ignacio's like: For real?
然后她说：那可不是么，我跟你说的这个事就是，但我不能告诉你线人是谁
And she's like: Yeah. You know what, I can't tell you who my contact is, because
因为他是跟复仇者一起的
he works with the Avengers.
哦不是吧！
Oh no.
是啊，他看起来可是个狠角色
Yeah, this dude sounds like a bad-ass, man.
他上来就这么问我
Like he comes up to him and he says, y'know:
我在找一个最近才出现的家伙，有某种特殊新技术
I'm looking for this dude who's new on the scene who's, like, flashing this fresh tack, who's got, like,
移动迅速，你有什么情报么？
bomb moves, right? Who you got?
然后她就说：那现在外面各种奇怪的人都有啊，会蹦高的
And she's like: Well, we got everything nowadays, we got a guy who jumps,
会甩丝荡秋千的，还有个能爬墙的
we got a guy who swings, we got a guy who crawls up the walls,
你得说的具体一点
you gotta be more specific.
然后他说，我在找一个能缩小的
And he's like: I'm looking for a guy that shrinks.
然后我听到这里差点吓尿了，我靠
And I'm like: Daaamn! I got all nervous 'cause
因为我从来没说过你的事儿哥们
I keep mad secrets for you, bro.
所以我就问伊格纳西奥
So I asked Ignacio:
那内个狠角色
Did bad-ass
有没有告诉超正记者妞来
tell the stupid fine writer chick
告诉你再告诉我
to tell you to tell me
就因为我跟他找的那个人有关系？
because I'm tight with that man that he's looking for him?
然后？
And?
他说什么？
What'd he say?
他说就是这么回事
He said yes.
我想给你看一样东西
There's something I want to show you.
我意识到力量是不能被摧毁的
I realized you can't destroy power.
我能做到的就是让它不落到坏人的手里
All you can do is make sure that it's in the right hands.
这是我和你妈妈研发的改进版原型装甲
This is an advanced prototype that your mother and I worked on together.
她一直没机会试过
She never got to use it.
直到现在我才意识到，我们其实是为你做的
But now I realize that we were, we were working on it for you.
也许是时候完成这件装甲了
Maybe it's time we finished it.
是时候了
It's about damn time.
嘿 队长！
Hey Cap!
帮帮我
Help...
要是早一个礼拜就好办多了
This would've been a lot easier a week ago.
- 如果我们找托尼… - 不要，他肯定不会信的 - 就算是他信了…
- If we call Tony... - No, he won't believe us. - Even if he did...
根据“协定”他也不一定能帮忙
Who knows if The Accords would let him help.
我们只能靠自己了
We're on our own.
也未必
Maybe not.
我知道个人
I know a guy.